Open the gate.
Öppna grinden.
You guys wanna step up to the table?
Kan ni gå fram till bordet?
Open the gate, please.
Öppna grinden, tack.
- Can I help you? - A dog.
- Kan jag hjälpa till? - En varmkorv.
Everything on it?
Med alla tillbehör?
Hey. Hey. Sixty-five cents.
Hallå. Sextiofem cent.
Mr. Frank, please.
Mr Frank, tack.
No.
Nej.
Well, my name's Dembo, A-20284.
Jag heter Dembo, A-20284.
Dembo, A-20284. Okay?
Dembo, A-20284. Okej?
Just tell him that I'm here and I'll just... I'll see him tomorrow morning.
Säg att jag var här och... Jag kan träffa honom i morgon.
I got an appointment with him. Nothing important.
Jag har avtalat möte med honom. Inget viktigt.
Yeah, okay. Thank you.
Ja, okej. Tack så mycket.
- Hi, Max. - Hi.
- Hej, Max. - Hej.
Earl Frank.
Earl Frank.
Come on in.
Kom in.
Have a seat.
Slå dig ner.
- You're a little late. - I had some trouble getting down here.
- Du är lite sen. - Jag hade problem att ta mig hit.
- Want a coffee? - Yeah, thanks.
- Vill du ha kaffe? - Ja tack.
Black.
Svart.
So fill me in. How was the trip?
Så berätta. Hur var resan?
On the bus down? It was a little long.
Bussen hit? Det tog lång tid.
- We made about 27 stops. - Yeah, it's a real milk train.
- Vi stannade nog 27 gånger. - Ja, det är ett riktigt mjölktåg.
Go ahead. Put it down on the floor.
Ställ den bara på golvet.
So, what'd you do last night?
Vad gjorde du i går kväll?
Oh, walked around.
Gick omkring.
- Meet anybody? - No, nobody I know.
- Träffade du någon? - Nej, ingen jag känner.
Where'd you stay? You didn't go to the halfway house.
Var sov du? Du var inte på halvvägshuset.
- I called. Didn't you get the message? - You called here?
- Jag ringde. Fick du inte meddelandet? - Ringde?
Last night. I left a message with your answering service.
I går kväll. Jag lämnade ett meddelande till dig.
- I didn't get it. - I left it.
- Jag fick det inte. - Jag lämnade det.
So where'd you sleep?
Så var sov du?
In a motel.
På motell.
The conditions of your parole were that you were to go to the house.
Villkoret för frigivningen var att du åkte dit.
That's a way to help you save money.
Det sparar pengar.
Now, you agreed to that before your release.
Du gick med på det innan frigivningen.
Why didn't you go there?
Varför åkte du inte dit?
Because I just spent six years in prison.
För att jag suttit inne i sex år.
I just wanted to look at the lights. I wanted to feel free.
Jag ville titta på ljusen. Jag ville känna mig fri.
I wanted to walk around...
Jag ville gå omkring...
...and not have somebody tell me that I gotta get in bed at 10:00.
...utan att någon sa till mig att jag måste lägga mig innan tio.
Max, I think you've got a serious attitude problem.
Max, jag tycker inte om din inställning.
I don't have an attitude.
Jag har ingen inställning.
Can you tell me what kind of attitude you want me to have?
Kan du säga vad för slags inställning du vill att jag ska ha?
Well, you don't decide whether or not you go to a halfway house.
Du bestämmer inte om du ska till halvvägshuset.
I mean, you come to me, we discuss it, then I decide.
Du kommer till mig, vi diskuterar, sen bestämmer jag.
I'm trying to make you understand, I'm aware of the realities of my situation...
Jag försöker få dig att förstå att jag är medveten om min situation.
...that I'm not fated to be a menace to society.
Att jag inte menad att vara en samhällsfara.
I'm not gonna go out and hit somebody over the head.
Jag ska inte gå ut och slå någon i huvudet.
My friend, I see that you're gonna force me to deal with you.
Jag ser att jag måste ta itu med dig.
I see that you've got juvenile offenses dating back to when you were 12.
Jag ser att du har begått brott sedan du var tolv.
I see you've got auto theft, you've got breaking and entering.
Jag ser att du stulit bilar och gjort inbrott.
All this leading up to a burglary warrant.
Det har lett till åtal för inbrott.
I just served six years for that chickenshit rap.
Jag har suttit inne i sex år för den skitsaken.
Chickenshit? You had a gun.
Skitsak? Du var beväpnad.
Yeah, but I didn't use it and I didn't hurt nobody.
Jag använde det inte och jag skadade ingen.
What was in your mind when you put it in your pocket?
Vad tänkte du när du tog med vapnet?
I just took it along.
Jag tog bara med det.
I'm due in court.
Jag måste till rätten.
I'm aware that you have this power, that you represent the state...
Jag vet att du har makt, att du representerar staten-
...but, you know, I think that you can give me a little leeway.
- men jag tycker att du kan ge mig lite spelrum.
You can be flexible.
Du kan vara flexibel.
I was just hoping to get some trust from you.
Jag hoppas att du litar på mig.
You've gotta earn the trust.
Det måste du förtjäna.
I have. I just wanna be like everybody else.
Det har jag. Jag vill bara vara som alla andra.
I just want a decent job. I want a decent place to live.
Jag vill ha ett anständigt jobb. Jag vill bo anständigt.
I want somebody to love me, I want some clothes on my back...
Jag vill ha någon som älskar mig, jag vill ha kläder...
...have some self-respect. - I gotta get going now.
...ha lite självkänsla. - Jag måste gå nu.
I tried to be straight with you, sir.
Jag försökte vara ärlig.
I shouldn't have done that last night without checking with you first.
Jag borde inte ha gjort så igår utan att ha kollat med dig först.
I'm sorry.
Jag ber om ursäkt.
I'll make a deal with you, Max.
Vi kan göra ett avtal, Max.
If you find a place to sleep today and a job by the end of the week...
Hittar du nånstans att sova idag och ett jobb till helgen-
...you don't have to go to a halfway house. Fair?
- behöver du inte åka till halvvägshuset.
That's fair. I appreciate that.
Det uppskattar jag.
When you find a place, you call Miss De Veccio and give her the address.
Ring miss De Veccio när du hittat ett ställe och ge henne adressen.
I'm gonna see you one day this week.
Vi träffas en dag denna veckan.
That's okay.
Det låter bra.
Here's the other hundred you've got coming to you.
Här är de resterande hundra som du har rätt till.
I want you to sign for it.
Jag vill att du kvitterar här.
Now, do you understand the conditions of your parole?
Förstår du villkoren för din frigivning?
- Yes, I do. - You have to attend all meetings.
- Ja. - Du måste gå på alla möten.
You must heed the advice and the counsel of your agent.
Du måste lyssna på din kontaktperson.
- Now, do you know what that means? - Yeah, I think I do.
- Förstår du vad det betyder? - Ja, det tror jag.
I gotta get along with you or you're gonna throw me back in jail.
Jag måste komma överens med dig annars sätter du mig i fängelse.
That's it in a nutshell.
I ett nötskal.
- You're a tough man. - No, I'm not, Max.
- Du är en hård man. - Nej, det är jag inte, Max.
All right, I gotta go now.
Nu måste jag gå.
- Good luck with it, now, huh? - Okay.
- Lycka till nu. - Okej.
I'm gonna do my best.
Jag ska göra mitt bästa.
- How much? - Eighteen dollars a week.
- Hur mycket? - Arton dollar i veckan.
Okay.
Okej.
- Here's your key. - Clean sheets?
- Här är din nyckel. - Rena lakan?
No. Bathroom is over there.
Nej. Badrummet är där borta.
Parole office. May I help you?
Frivårdsmyndigheten.
Could you leave a message for Mr. Frank?
Kan ni lämna ett meddelande till mr Frank?
- Who 's calling? - My name is Max Dembo, A-20284.
- Vem är det från? - Jag heter Max Dembo, A-20284.
- What? - I got that.
- Vad? - Jag uppfattade det.
- A-20284. - Thank you.
- A-20284. - Tack.
Could you tell him I'm at the Garland Hotel?
Kan ni säga att jag bor på Garland Hotel?
That's G-A-R-L-A-N-D.
Det stavas G-A-R-L-A-N-D.
And you'd better give him the phone number. It's 321-1321.
Det är bäst att han får telefonnumret. Det är 321-1321.
- I'll give him the message. - I'd appreciate it if he gets it today.
- Jag ger honom meddelandet. - Jag uppskattar om han får det idag.
- I'll give him the message, sir. - Okay, thank you. Bye-bye.
- Tack ska du ha. Hej då.
Time's up.
Tiden är slut.
- Time's up. I'm sorry. - I just wanted to finish that sentence.
- Tiden är slut. Jag är ledsen. - Jag ville bara avsluta meningen.
Bring those score sheets.
Ta med papprena.
You did great on your intelligence test.
Du fick bra på intelligenstestet.
Yeah, well, you know. I could have told you that.
Ja, du vet, det kunde jag ha sagt.
One moment.
Ett ögonblick.
Wilshire Agency.
Wilshire-förmedlingen.
Yes, she is. Hold on.
Ja, ett ögonblick.
Pat, it's for you.
Pat, det är till dig.
- Did you put it on hold, honey? - Yeah.
- Parkerade du det? - Ja.
Hello?
Hallå?
Disconnected. I lost the call.
Avbrutet. Jag missade samtalet.
You're supposed to push down "Hold" before you use these other buttons.
Du ska trycka på "parkera" innan du trycker på de andra knapparna.
- There's "Hold," there's the buttons. - Okay.
- Där är "parkera", där är knapparna. - Okej.
I'm sorry.
Förlåt.
- Did you just get this job? - Yeah. I've had it about a week.
- Är du ny här? - Ja, jag har jobbat här i en vecka.
- Is she your boss? - Yeah.
- Är hon din chef? - Ja.
Does she really like you as much as she seems to?
Tycker hon om dig så mycket som det verkar?
I guess. I don't know.
Jag antar det. Jag vet inte.
You got a 61 on your typing test.
Du fick 61 på maskinskrivningen.
- Is that bad? - I'm afraid it's a little low.
- Är det lågt? - Det är lite lågt, är jag rädd.
Well, I'm not used to the electric.
Jag är inte van vid elektrisk.
What was your last place of employment?
Vilken var din senaste arbetsplats?
Were you self-employed or in the armed services?
Hade du en firma eller var du i försvaret?
No. I didn't know whether to put down "state penitentiary."
Nej, jag visste inte om jag skulle skriva "fängelse".
I was a convict.
Jag var intern.
And how long did you hold that position?
Hur länge hade du den anställningen?
Approximately six years. No vacation.
Cirka sex år. Utan semester.
What'd you do?
Vad hade du gjort?
Burglary.
Inbrott.
You know, I know I fouled up that typing test...
Jag vet att jag körde på maskinskrivningen-
...but I do know how to work a manual...
- men jag kan hantera manuell.
...and if you get any calls for a manual typist...
Om någon behöver en manuell maskinskrivare-
...I'd appreciate it, you know?
- så skulle jag uppskatta det.
Well, I'll see what I can do.
Jag ska se vad jag kan göra.
All I wanna...
Allt jag vill...
All I wanna do is get a job.
Allt jag vill är att få ett jobb.
I need a fucking job.
Jag behöver ett jävla jobb.
I believe you.
Jag tror dig.
Well, let me see.
Låt mig se.
I'm sorry to be a problem.
Ursäkta att jag ställer till problem.
You know, like I can't drive a car without permission.
Jag kan inte köra bil utan tillåtelse, vet du.
- Why not? - Well, it's a parole restriction.
- Varför inte? - Det strider mot villkoren.
I can't handle money, you know, and it's like I'm limited...
Jag får inte hantera pengar, och jag är förhindrad-
...in terms of what they allow me to do.
- i och med vad de låter mig göra.
Is there anything at all?
Finns det något alls?
How about the National Can Company?
Kanske National Can Company?
- Think they'd let you work there? - Yeah.
- Tror du det går bra? - Ja.
- I think that'd be all right with them. - It's not much. It's only scale.
- Jag tror att det skulle gå bra. - Det är inte mycket. Det är vägning.
You wanna try? Okay.
Vill du försöka med det?
Let's see what we've got here.
Låt oss se vad vi har här.
Well, go here and see what they say.
Gå dit och se vad de säger.
Listen, if I get this job, can I celebrate by taking you to dinner?
Om jag får jobbet, får jag bjuda dig på middag och fira?
You're not sure?
Är du osäker?
Is that a half yes?
Är det ett halvt ja?
I guess so.
Jag antar det.
When you go there, I hope you get the job.
Jag hoppas du får jobbet.
- Thanks for your time. - Good luck.
- Tack för hjälpen. - Lycka till.
- Thank you. - Let me know what happens.
- Tack. - Låt mig veta hur det går.
Okay.
Okej.
- Hello? Who is it? - Who is this?
- Hallå? Vem är det? - Vem är det här?
This is Henry Darin.
Det är Henry Darin.
- Henry Darin? I've heard about you. - Yeah.
- Jag har hört talas om dig. - Ja.
- Is your daddy there?
- Är din pappa där?
Well, you tell him that somebody wants to give the big bear a bear hug.
Säg att någon vill ge den stora björnen en björnkram.
- Who is it? - Just tell him...
- Vem är det? - Säg att...
...somebody wants to give the big bear a bear hug. He'll know.
...någon vill ge björnen en björnkram. Han förstår.
Dad! Someone wants to give you a big-bear big bear hug!
Pappa! Någon vill ge dig en stor-björn stor björnkram!
- Hello? - Willy?
- Hallå? - Willy?
- Yeah? - It's Max.
- Ja? - Det är Max.
Dembo?
Dembo?
- How you doing? - Max, thank... Goddamn.
- Hur är det? - Max, tack... vad fan.
- Is that your boy? - Yeah.
- Är det din pojke? - Ja.
The last time you wrote, he was learning how to walk.
Senast du skrev, höll han på att lära sig gå.
Well, where the hell are you?
Var i helvete är du?
I got no wheels yet. You wanna come get me?
Jag har ingen kärra än. Hämtar du mig?
Yes! Tell me where you are.
Ja. Var är du?
Well, why don't I meet you on 7th and Alvarado?
Kan vi träffas i hörnet 7th och Alvarado?
- If I'm not there, wait for me, all right? - Okay.
- Om jag inte är där, vänta, okej? - Okej.
- You coming now? - I'm coming now.
- Kommer du nu? - Jag kommer nu.
- Okay. I'll see you. - Okay. Yeah.
- Okej. Vi ses. - Javisst.
- How you doing? - Good. Get in the back, Bart. In the back!
- Hur är det? - Bra. Gå tillbaks, Bart!
- How you doing? Good to see you. - It's going well.
- Hur är det? Kul att se dig. - Det går bra.
Good. Rock 'n' roll!
Bra. Toppen!
- How you doing? - Doing good.
- Hur är det med dig? - Det går bra.
- You working? - I'm riveting.
- Jobbar du? - Jag nitar.
Kitchens and bathrooms in portable homes.
Kök och badrum i flyttbara hem.
How'd you get the job?
Hur fick du jobbet?
Well, when I came out, the parole officer got it for me...
När jag kom ut fixade handläggaren det åt mig.
...and when I got off parole, Selma said, "It's good enough. Why not keep it?"
När den villkorliga var slut, sa Selma att det var ett bra jobb.
You'll be a riveter the rest of your life, man.
Du kommer att nita resten av livet.
Shit, no, man. I'm working on my time.
I helvete heller.
I'm getting my drums together. I'm gonna play.
Jag fixar mina trummor. Jag ska spela.
Holy Jesus!
Herre Jesus!
- You the one I talked to on the phone? - Shake hands with Max Dembo.
- Är det dig jag pratade med? - Hälsa på Max Dembo.
- This is my son, Henry. - How you doing?
- Det här är Max Dembo, Henry. - Hur är det?
Tell him a knock-knock joke. He's got tons.
Dra ett knack-knack-skämt.
- Knock-knock. - Who's there?
- Knack-knack. - Vem är det?
- You. - You who?
- Du. - Vilken du?
Gotcha. I know that one.
Jag fick dig. Jag kunde det.
Hey, look what I found downtown, Mama.
Titta vad jag hittade på stan!
Henry.
Henry.
- Come on, Bart! - Get inside there.
- Kom, Bart! - Gå in.
- Hello, Max. - Hi, Selma.
- Hej, Max. - Hej, Selma.
- You didn't bring any beer, did you? - Was I supposed to?
- Du har inte med öl? - Skulle jag det?
- I got it. - Good.
- Jag fixade det. - Bra.
How about some spaghetti?
Vad sägs om spaghetti?
- Get inside. Get in, come on. - Oh, God. Jesus, come on inside.
- Kom in. - Ja, jösses, kom in.
- Come on, come on. Get in. - God dog, that smells good.
Det luktar gott.
Show Max your muscle. Make it. Make it big.
Visa Max din muskel. Gör den stor.
Pretty hard. Let me see the other one.
Riktigt hård. Få se den andra.
Make two of them. Two of them at once, here.
Visa båda två nu.
You work out?
Tränar du?
Does he work out? Come here.
Tränar han? Kom här.
- Show Max what we do on Saturdays. - You teaching him to defend himself?
- Visa Max vad vi gör på lördagarna. - Lär du honom självförsvar?
You bet your ass. On our days off.
Visst. På våra lediga dagar.
- How could you teach him? - Got one in.
Hur kan du lära honom?
Got one in there. Come on.
Få in en där. Okej.
- Okay, okay. - He's gonna whip your ass.
Han kommer att ge dig stryk
Where's them cigars?
Var är cigarrerna?
Hey. I told...
Hör du. Jag sa...
So he's...
Så han...
Don't be hitting me when I'm not looking at you.
Du ska inte slå mig när jag inte tittar på dig.
Oh, he's just playing.
Han leker bara.
You defend yourself pretty good there.
Du försvarar dig rätt bra.
- You been in many fights? - Yeah, 10.
- Har du varit i många slagsmål? - Ja, tio.
- Ten? Not bad. How many you won? - Eighteen.
- Inte illa. Hur många har du vunnit? - Arton.
Really? That's not a bad record.
Det var inte dåligt.
Eighteen out of 10.
Arton av tio möjliga.
Hey, how you feel? You wanna go out and hit the tubs?
Hur känner du dig? Vill du ut och slå lite på tunnorna?
- Yeah. - Let's go.
- Ja. - Kom då.
I think he'd better go in and clean up his room now.
Jag tycker att han ska städa sitt rum nu.
Selma, let me have about 10 minutes with him, because I wanna make it...
Låt mig få 10 minuter med honom för jag vill göra det...
- I didn't mean to get mad. - I know.
- Jag menade inte att bli arg. - Jag vet.
- He's gotta get to bed early, okay? - Just let... We...
- Han måste bara lägga sig i tid. - Låt mig bara... vi...
Let him go in and clean up his room, okay?
Låt honom städa sitt rum, okej?
He's gotta get up early tomorrow morning.
Han ska upp tidigt i morgon.
- Okay? - Okay.
- Okej? - Okej.
Come here. I get a kiss.
Kom. Ge mig en puss.
- I get one too. Good night. - Give Max a kiss. That's it.
- Jag vill ha en med. God natt. - Ge Max en puss. Så där ja.
Everybody gets a kiss.
Alla får en puss.
- Hey, I'm sorry. - Okay.
- Förlåt. - Okej.
I didn't mean to get mad.
Jag menade inte att bli arg.
Okay?
Okej?
Didn't mean to get mad at you.
Jag menade inte att bli arg på dig.
See you later. Excuse me.
Vi ses senare. Ursäkta mig.
I'll be getting that board together.
Jag ska fixa skivan.
You got any more coffee?
Finns det mer kaffe?
That Henry is a nice boy.
Henry är en fin grabb.
Yes, he is.
Ja, det är han.
Come here, man. Get up here.
Kom här.
Come on. Get up here.
Kom igen.
Sit up here. Smart dog.
Kom upp här. Duktig vovve.
Come here.
Kom här.
Want something to eat? Okay if I give him some ice cream?
Vill du ha något att äta? Får jag ge honom lite glass?
Sure. He'll eat anything,
Visst. Han äter vad som helst.
Next time I'm down here, I'm gonna bring him a steak bone.
Nästa gång jag kommer, ska jag ta med ett ben.
In fact, as soon as Willy turns his back, I'm gonna steal this dog.
Så fort Willy vänder ryggen till, ska jag faktiskt ta hunden.
You know, Max, I don't wanna hurt your feelings...
Vet du, Max, jag vill inte såra dig-
...but your being around here is kind of bad timing for us.
- men att du är här passar inte så bra för oss.
Why is that?
Hur menar du?
Well, Willy's been doing real good, you know.
Willy har klarat sig riktigt bra.
He's been doing real fine. He's been working hard lately.
Han har klarat sig bra. Han har jobbat hårt på sistone.
And I know you're good friends and he really loves you...
Jag vet att ni är goda vänner och han älskar dig verkligen...
...but I just don't think it's good that he see you right now.
...men jag tycker inte att det är bra att han träffar dig nu.
You know what I mean?
Förstår du?
You trying to tell me you don't want me to come here no more?
Vill du inte att jag kommer hit igen?
I don't mean to be unkind.
Jag menar inget illa.
I just think it's better that he doesn't get around other influences and stuff.
Jag tror bara att det är bättre om han inte utsätts för influenser.
You're on parole now, Max.
Du är villkorligt frigiven, Max.
Well, you really shouldn't even be seen with Willy, right?
Du borde inte ens umgås med Willy, eller hur?
I think I get the message.
Jag förstår.
You make me feel bad.
Nu känner jag mig dum.
Why? You're just doing what you have to do, Selma.
Varför? Du gör bara det du måste.
It's no problem.
Det är inga problem.
It's cool.
Det är lugnt.
This is it.
Här är det.
- Here. Let me get it. - I'll get the front.
- Låt mig ta den. - Jag tar där fram.
- You sure? - Yeah.
- Är du säker? - Ja.
- All right. It's three flights up. - I gotta piss, so you'd better run.
- Det är tre trappor upp. - Jag måste pissa, så spring.
All right.
Visst.
Remember that place called The Hague? Right across from the Cocoanut Grove.
Kommer du ihåg stället The Hague? Tvärs över från Coconut Grove.
- Where do you want it? - Put it underneath the bed there.
- Var vill du ha den? - Lägg den under sängen där.
Last time I was there, Hampton Hawes and Chet Baker were playing there.
Sist jag var där spelade Hampton Hawes och Chet Baker.
- Is it still open? - I don't know.
- Finns det fortfarande? - Jag vet inte.
- Three flights of stairs killed me. - Go back in the joint, you'll get in shape.
- Tre tappor tog kål på mig. - Åk in igen, så kommer du i form.
- Hold it up. - I got it.
- Håll upp den. - Jag har den.
- You sure it don't have termites? - It's okay.
- Säkert att den inte har termiter? - Ja.
How does it feel? That's the main thing.
Hur känns det? Det är huvudsaken.
It's good, isn't it?
Det blev bra, eller hur?
I know where we could go.
Jag vet vart vi kan gå.
- The Autoway Club. - The what?
- The Autoway Club. - Vart?
The Autoway Club. Remember that? We used to go there?
The Autoway Club. Vi brukade gå dit?
- We could go. - Do a little fucking around, maybe.
- Det kan vi. - Kanske får vi hugg.
Yeah. Maybe we could go to Hermosa Beach too.
Kanske kunde vi gå till Hermosa Beach också.
Oh, yeah.
Ja.
- Howard Rumsey... - Yeah.
- Howard Rumsey... - Ja.
...and his Lighthouse All-Stars.
...och hans Lighthouse All-Stars.
All right, let's go there. Maybe there'll be some nice little girls there I can...
Visst, vi sticker dit. Kanske finns det några flickor jag kan...
You can get me three years for that.
Det kan jag få tre år för.
Sorry.
Förlåt.
I got excited, that's all.
Jag blev bara lite uppspelt.
Does Selma know you're using?
Vet Selma vad du gör?
Well, she's always suspicious.
Hon är alltid misstänksam.
The machine broke down, so I gotta stay.
Bilen gick sönder, så jag måste stanna.
What do you want me to tell you? I'll probably be about two or three hours.
Vad kan jag säga? Det tar nog två eller tre timmar.
Well, I'm glad.
Vad bra.
All right. Bye.
Visst. Hej då.
- Hello. Jenny Mercer speaking. - Hi. How you doing? This is Max Dembo.
- Hallå. Jenny Mercer. - Hej. Hur är det? Det är Max Dembo.
Thank you for making me a bona fide member of society.
Tack för att jag blivit en fullvärdig medlem av samhället.
Oh, you got the job? That's great.
Fick du jobbet? Vad bra.
- Why don't you have dinner with me? - When?
- Vill du äta middag med mig? - När?
I could be there in an hour and a half. I wanna go shower and change.
Om en och en halv timme. Jag vill duscha och byta om.
Actually, I was planning on staying home tonight.
Jag hade tänkt vara hemma i kväll.
It's just that it's the first chance I have to celebrate something.
Det är min första chans att fira något.
You know? I want to...
Jag skulle vilja...
You know, I wanna have a steak. I thought you could keep me company.
Jag vill ha en biff. Du kan göra mig sällskap.
- I don't even know what to order. - Okay.
- Jag vet inte vad jag ska beställa. - Okej.
- Is that okay? - Yeah.
- Är det okej? - Ja.
All right, can I be at your office, let's say about 5:30?
Kan jag vara vid ditt jobb vid halv sex?
- See you then. - All right.
- Vi ses. - Ja visst.
- Bye. - Bye-bye.
- Hej då.
All I'm saying is, out here, the rules aren't defined. On the inside, they are.
Här ute är reglerna inte klara. Där inne är de det.
If you don't pay back your debts, if you owe a couple packs of cigarettes...
Om man inte betalar sina skulder, om man är skyldig ett cigarettpaket-
...if you take somebody's glove or lie to someone, then you get killed.
- tar man en handske eller ljuger, så blir man dödad.
You know that's the rules, so you live by them.
Man kan reglerna, så man följer dem.
You can get killed with a sharp edge...
Man kan bli dödad med den vassa änden-
...the end of this spoon.
- av den här skeden.
That's a lethal weapon.
Det är ett dödligt vapen.
Even the end of a toothbrush.
Till och med en tandborste.
You can get hit in the yard or you can get it in the shower.
De kan slå till ute på gården eller i duschen.
You're in your cell sleeping, someone can go by with a can of gas and throw it in.
Ligger man i cellen och sover kan nån kasta in en gasburk.
Somebody else throws in a match and you're torched.
Någon tänder och man brinner upp.
You know that's the reality and you're living with it 24 hours a day.
Det är verkligheten och man lever med det dygnet runt.
That's frightening.
Skrämmande.
A lot of guys think this is more frightening, being on the outside.
Många av grabbarna tycker att det här är mer skrämmande.
Why? I don't understand.
Varför? Jag förstår inte.
Because out here, it's what you got in your pocket that matters...
För här ute är det vad man har i fickan som betyder något-
...and on the inside, it's only what you are.
- på insidan är det vem du är som är viktigt.
You're glad to be out, aren't you?
Du är väl glad att vara ute?
It's like a dream. It's every con's fantasy to be out here.
Det är som en dröm. Det är varje fånges dröm att vara här.
I can't tell you the number of times I thought about a scene just like this...
Jag kan inte säga hur många gånger jag tänkt på en sån här scen.
...but I never thought I'd be sitting here with a knot in my stomach.
Men jag trodde aldrig att jag skulle sitta här med fjärilar i magen.
Tell me more about that guy you were going with.
Berätta om killen du var ihop med.
How long were you with him?
Hur länge var ni tillsammans?
I lived with him for about two years.
Vi bodde ihop i två år.
Who broke it off?
Vem gjorde slut?
I did.
Jag.
Thank you very much. Come on back again.
Tack så mycket. Välkomna tillbaka.
Wanna know something? I'm glad you asked me out.
Vill du veta en sak? Jag är glad att du bjöd ut mig.
Don't you have enough money?
Har du inte tillräckligt med pengar?
I think I got enough for the tax.
Jag har nog till momsen.
Here, I've got some.
Här, jag har lite.
Wait a minute. I wanted this to be my treat.
Vänta lite. Jag ville bjuda.
Why don't we just walk out?
Varför går vi inte bara ut?
You don't wanna do that, do you?
Du vill inte det, va?
I'll make a deal. If you'll go out with me tomorrow night, I'll let you help me.
Om du går ut med mig i morgon så låter jag dig hjälpa mig.
Okay, you've got a deal.
Okej, vi gör så.
All right, be discreet and slip it under the table.
Var diskret och skicka det under bordet.
Hi, how you doing?
Hej, hur är det?
Okay.
Bra.
I was in the neighborhood, so I had your manager let me in.
Jag var i närheten, så jag bad dem släppa in mig.
- Mind if I come in? - Sure. Come on, it's your home.
- Får jag komma in? - Visst, kom in. Det är ditt hem.
I mean, this is just routine, you know.
Det här är bara rutin.
It's a nice room. You've got cross-ventilation. Nice view.
Trevligt rum. Du har korsdrag. Fin utsikt.
- Yeah, it's nice. - What they charge you for?
- Ja, det är trevligt. - Vad tar de för det?
It's $ 17 a week.
17 dollar i veckan.
- That's better than $ 17 in a motel. - Yeah.
- Det är bättre än 17 dollar per natt. - Ja.
- You're right. - I know.
- Du har rätt. - Jag vet.
Do you mind if I change? I gotta be somewhere in a half-hour.
Kan jag byta om? Jag ska iväg om en halvtimme.
No, go right ahead. Don't let me hold you up. Go ahead.
Låt mig inte hindra dig.
- What do you got, a date? - Yeah.
- Ska du på en dejt? - Ja.
Is she white?
Är hon vit?
I'm just joking.
Jag skojade bara.
So...
Så...
...who is she?
...vem är hon?
I met her at the employment agency. She works there.
Jag träffade henne på arbetsförmedlingen.
In fact, she sent me for a job and I went over there and I got it.
Hon skickade mig på intervju och jag fick jobbet.
Great. Great. What kind of work is it?
Toppen. Vad är det för jobb?
Well, it's just a can company, you know.
Det är en konservfabrik.
- Regular wage? - Yeah.
- Avtalsenlig lön? - Ja.
Well, that's a start. Did you tell them you were on parole?
Det är en början. Sa du att du är villkorlig frigiven?
No. Is that a problem?
Nej. Är det ett problem?
Oh, no worry. I can take care of that.
Oroa dig inte. Jag tar hand om det.
You've got a room, you've got a job, the whole...
Du har ett rum, du har ett jobb...
You gave me a week, so yeah. It's over in Verona.
Du gav mig en vecka, så... Det är i Verona.
What's this?
Vad är det här?
- Just matches. - I know that.
- Tändstickor. - Jag vet det.
Take off your shirt. Let's see your arms.
Ta av dig. Få se armarna.
- They're not mine. - Max, take off your shirt.
- De är inte mina. - Ta av dig skjortan.
What's this?
Vad är det här?
That's just a scratch I got on the job today. It's not tracks.
Det är ett skrapsår jag fick på jobbet. Det är inte nålstick.
- Let me see this one. - You won't find nothing.
- Få se på den. - Du hittar ingenting.
Just let me do my work.
Låt mig göra mitt jobb.
- Where'd you get all those scars? - It's just burns.
- Hur har du fått ärren? - Det är brännsår.
- When you were a kid? - Yeah, it was an accident.
- När du var liten? - Ja, det var en olycka.
Does it hurt?
Gör det ont?
Let me see the other one.
Få se på den andra.
Did you hear about the Polack who got third-degree burns on his face?
Hörde du om polacken som brände sig i ansiktet?
He was dunking for french fries.
Han dök efter pommes frites.
Been drinking some beer, huh?
Du har druckit öl, va?
Yeah. Just a couple cans, though.
Ja. Fast bara några burkar.
- What are you doing? - Come on, Max.
- Vad gör du? - Kom igen, Max.
Come on, Max. Come on, now. Take it easy.
Ta det lugnt nu.
Why'd you do that? You didn't have to chain me.
Varför gjorde du så?
- It's procedure. - I told you, I'm clean.
- Det är reglementet. - Jag är ren.
Then you got nothing to worry about.
Då är det ingen fara.
Just come over here and check me if you got a doubt.
Kom och kolla mig om du tvivlar.
- If you're clean... - What do you mean, "if"?
- Om du är ren... - Vad menar du?
You didn't check me properly. Did you check my eyes?
Du har inte kollat ordentligt.
If you're clean, you got nothing to worry about.
Om du är ren, är det ingen fara.
I gotta make a phone call, then we'll take you down and test you.
Jag ska ringa ett samtal, sen åker vi och testar dig.
- I could save you a lot of trouble. - It's no trouble. It's what I get paid for.
- Jag kan bespara dig omaket. - Det är inget omak. Jag gör mitt jobb.
We're just playing a game.
Vi leker bara.
All right. Come on, follow me.
Kom igen, följ med här.
Come on. Keep it up.
Kom igen, häng med.
All right, move right in here.
Kom in här.
- Gentlemen, follow the red line. - Take your hat off.
- Mina herrar, följ den röda linjen. - Ta av mössan.
- Right in the corner, facing me.
- In i hörnet, ansiktet mot mig.
Start with you, right over in this corner. Facing me, gentlemen.
Vi börjar med dig, inne i hörnet. Ansiktena mot mig.
Everybody facing me.
Alla vänder sig mot mig.
In case you don't know where you are, this is the Los Angeles County Jail.
I fall ni inte vet var ni är, så är detta häktet i Los Angeles.
Welcome, and empty your pockets on the floor. Everything out.
Välkomna, och töm ut fickornas innehåll på golvet. Allt ska ut.
Cigarettes, money, matches, everything. On the floor.
Cigaretter, pengar, tändstickor, allt. Ut på golvet.
Turn your pockets inside out after you get everything out.
Vänd fickorna ut och in efter att ni tömt dem.
Okay, gentlemen, I want you to run your fingers through your hair.
Jag vill att ni drar fingrarna genom håret.
Shake it out good.
Skaka igenom det.
- Is that a wig? - Yeah, it's a wig.
- Är det en peruk? - Ja, det är en peruk.
Take it off. Put it on the floor.
Ta av den. Lägg den på golvet.
Run your hands through your hair.
Dra fingrarna genom håret.
Okay, gentlemen, put your hands out in front of you, palms up.
Mina herrar, håll händerna framför er. Handflatorna uppåt.
Okay, turn over.
Vänd på dem.
Okay, gentlemen, turn around and grab a piece of the wall.
Mina herrar, vänd er om och håll i väggen.
Step back. Spread your feet.
Kliv ut. Sära på fötterna.
As soon as you take your clothes off, I want you to sit on a bench.
Så fort ni tagit av er kläderna, vill jag att ni sätter er ner.
Okay, move on.
Fortsätt.
Don't be afraid to use some soap.
Var inte rädda att använda tvålen.
All right, gentlemen, you in the shower, let's move it out.
Ni i duschen dags att röra på sig.
We don't have all day. That water's not free.
Vi har inte hela dagen på oss. Vatten är inte gratis.
Take your showers and get out.
Ta er dusch och gå vidare.
As soon as you step out of your shower, grab a towel and step over on the side.
Så fort ni stiger ur duschen, tar ni en handduk och stiger undan.
Dry yourself off thoroughly.
Torka er ordentligt.
Let's go, gentlemen.
Då rör vi på oss.
Turn around.
Vänd er.
- Go. Let's go, arms up. - If you were on a bench, get a shower.
- Kom igen, upp med armarna. - Satt ni ner, ta en dusch.
- Small, medium or large? - Medium.
- Small, medium eller large? - Medium.
- Head down. Turn around. Go. - Let's go, gentlemen.
- Ner med huvudet. Vänd er om. - Då går vi.
Get out of the shower and dry off. We don't have enough time.
Ut ur duschen och torka er. Vi har inte tillräckligt med tid.
- Let's go. Move it out. - Good hands, Pop.
- Rör på er. - Bra händer, farsan.
That one's mine, partner.
Den är min.
Stand clear!
Håll undan!
Dembo! Visit!
Dembo! Besök!
- Hi, remember me? - Yeah. How you doing?
- Kommer du ihåg mig? - Ja, hur är det?
- Pretty good. How are you? - I'm fine.
- Ganska bra. Hur har du det? - Bra.
I called and your landlady told me you were arrested. What happened?
Jag ringde och värden sa att du blev gripen. Vad hände?
I don't know.
Jag vet inte.
Doesn't matter.
Spelar ingen roll.
I got worried. I was waiting and...
Jag blev orolig. Jag väntade och...
When are you getting out?
När kommer du ut?
I don't know. It's a little hard to say.
Jag vet inte. Det är svårt att säga.
You don't mind my coming here, do you?
Det gör väl inget att jag kom?
I called earlier and they said the visiting room closes at 3.
Jag ringde tidigare och de sa att besökstiden tar slut vid tre.
I got lost on the way.
Jag hittade inte.
Is there anything I can do?
Kan jag göra något?
- No, it's all right. - What?
- Nej, det är bra. - Vad?
Oh, God, there's no more time. Wait a second.
Tiden är ute. Vänta lite.
- I gotta go. - Wait. Wait.
- Jag måste gå. - Vänta.
Call me when you get out.
Ring när du kommer ut.
Call me. It's my home phone.
Ring. Det är mitt hemnummer.
Okay?
Okej?
This terrific-Iooking blond goes into this dentist's office and she's really scared.
En snygg blondin går till tandläkaren och hon är rädd.
She climbs up into the chair as the dentist prepares his utensils and things.
Hon sätter sig i stolen medan tandläkaren förbereder instrumenten.
And just as he turns around and is about to look into her mouth...
När han just ska titta i hennes mun-
...she blurts out, "Oh, doctor, I'm so afraid of dentists...
- säger hon "Jag är så rädd för tandläkare-
...I think I'd rather have a baby than have a tooth drilled."
- jag skulle hellre föda barn än få en tand borrad."
"Well, miss," the doctor says, "you'd better make up your mind...
Och han svarar "Det är bäst att du bestämmer dig-
...before I adjust the chair."
- innan jag ställer in stolen."
So how you doing?
Hur har du det?
How do you think I'm doing, slammed down?
Hur tror du, när jag sitter inne?
What?
Va?
I'm okay.
Det är bra.
Listen, your urine tested clean.
Ditt urinprov var rent.
I'm sorry you got stuck here, but I've had my hands full this week.
Jag är ledsen att du blev fast här, men det var körigt.
- This is the first time I could reach you. - Did the phones break down?
- Det är först nu jag kunde nå dig. - Var telefonen trasig?
Don't get sarcastic with me, Dembo.
Var inte sarkastisk mot mig.
I'm having you released from here. I'll take you to a halfway house myself.
Jag ska få dig utsläppt. Jag kör dig själv till halvvägshuset.
- When is that? Now? - Right now.
- När då? Nu? - Ja, just nu.
I think that's more than generous.
Det är mer än generöst.
You're the boss.
Du bestämmer.
Right. You're smart enough to recognize a break when you get one.
Bra. Du är smart nog att känna igen en chans när du får en.
Now, you were clean, but somebody fixed in your room.
Du var ren, men någon rökte på i ditt rum.
That's a violation of your parole and it's enough to get you...
Det bryter mot frigivningen och det kan ge dig-
...a minimum of two to three years.
- minst två till tre år.
Am I right?
Stämmer det?
- So we'll start from scratch. - Sure.
- Så vi börjar från början. - Visst.
We'll get you cleaned up and we'll get you out of here.
Vi städar upp dig och får ut dig härifrån.
- Okay. - All right.
- Visst. - Bra.
Sometimes this job is getting to be too much.
Ibland blir jobbet för mycket.
You wouldn't believe the week I had last week.
Förra veckan var helt otrolig.
I missed my girl's school play. My wife was so pissed off at me...
Jag missade min dotters skolpjäs. Min fru var så arg-
...I thought she was gonna divorce me.
- att skilsmässan var nära.
On top of that, I got a call that one of my guys was holed up in his house.
Dessutom hade en av mina killar stängt in sig i ett hus.
Threatening his wife with a shotgun. Guess how I handled that one.
Han hotade frun med en hagelbössa. Gissa vad jag gjorde.
I used my head.
Jag använde huvudet.
I called his father in Detroit...
Jag ringde hans pappa i Detroit-
...then I got them talking on the phone. They must have talked for three hours.
- och fick dem att prata. De måste ha pratat i tre timmar.
All this is person-to-person. It's costing the state.
Såna långdistanssamtal. Det kostar staten pengar.
- Top of the seventh inning, Dodgers leading 10-2. Scored 10 each game.
...Dodgers ledde med 10-2.
Damn it. You know, I had 10 bucks on that game.
Fan också. Jag hade satt tio dollar i den matchen.
Everything you got check out?
Har du fått allt?
- Yeah. - Good.
- Ja. - Bra.
Cooking spoon's not there, is it?
Pipan är inte där, eller?
Come on. Just between you and me, this doesn't go any further...
Bara mellan dig och mig, det går inte vidare-
...who was it shot up in your room?
- vem var det som rökte på?
I just can't tell you that.
Jag kan inte säga det.
I'm taking you to a halfway house. I'm not taking you back to the joint.
Jag tar dig till halvvägshuset. Jag tar dig inte till fängelset.
You asked for my trust. I'm giving it to you.
Du bad om tillit. Du får det.
- How about giving a little back in return? - I can't tell you that.
- Kan du inte ge något tillbaka? - Jag kan inte säga det.
Bullshit. If you can't trust me, what the hell, I'm just wasting gas driving.
Skitsnack. Om du inte litar på mig då slösar jag bara bensin, för fan.
- I don't want you to waste your gas. - Then tell me who it was.
- Jag vill inte slösa din bensin. - Säg då vem det var.
Christ, you're gonna kill us!
Jösses, du tar livet av oss!
Put them down. Go on.
Sluta nu.
Don't fuck with me, sucker. You busted me for nothing!
Jävlas inte med mig. Du satte dit mig för ingenting!
You big, bald fucker!
Din stora, flintiga jävel!
You're finished. You made your choice.
Du är färdig. Du har gjort ditt val.
Max!
Max!
- Damn you sons of bitches! - Hey, fatso, where's your pants?
- Fan ta er, era jävlar! - Hörru fetto, var har du byxorna?
- Hey, how you doing, man? - Hey, my friend.
- Hej, hur är det? - Min vän.
- How you been? - Haven't seen you in a while.
- Hur har du haft det? - Jag har inte sett dig på ett tag.
I know, I got hung up for a while.
Jag var upptagen.
- What you got going? - I need your car.
- Vad har du på gång? - Jag behöver din bil.
- The keys are in it. - All right.
Nycklarna sitter i.
- Hey, take me with you. - I can't. I gotta see some people.
- Jag vill följa med. - Nej, jag ska träffa lite folk.
Be back in a couple hours.
Kommer om några timmar.
- Next time, I wanna go with you. - All right, you got it.
- Nästa gång vill jag följa med. - Visst, det får du.
- I'm not shitting you. - I hear you.
- Jag skämtar inte. - Okej.
- If I go with you, I can drive. I can get... - You got it.
- Om jag är med, kan jag köra. - Du får det.
Hey, my radio.
Min radio.
I'll be back, couple hours.
Jag kommer om några timmar.
Where's he going?
Vart ska han?
He's going to the store. He'll be back in a minute.
Han skulle till affären. Han kommer snart.
- How are you? What's to it, Manny? - How you doing, man?
Hur är det, Manny?
- How are you? - I'm all right.
- Hur är det? - Det är bra.
I wanna talk.
Jag behöver snacka.
- Yeah. - I mean right now, okay?
- Visst. - Jag menar nu.
- If anybody asks for me, I'm not here. - All right.
- Jag är inte här om någon frågar. - Visst.
- What do you wanna talk about? - I just need your help.
- Vad vill du prata om? - Jag behöver din hjälp.
- What do you want, money? - I want a pistol.
- Behöver du pengar? - Jag behöver en pistol.
No, I don't do that, Max.
Jag gör inte sånt, Max.
- You don't keep a piece in your office? - I don't play around with guns.
- Har du inte en på ditt kontor? - Jag sysslar inte med vapen.
You owe me one, Manny. You owe me one.
Du är skyldig mig, Manny.
Come on.
Kom igen.
Shut the door.
Stäng dörren.
- I got something we took off a drunk. - Just give me what you have.
- Jag har en jag tog från ett fyllo. - Ge mig det du har.
I just gotta get my hands on some heavy stuff, you know?
Jag behöver tyngre grejer, du vet?
I need a Thompson, you know, a Magnum.
Jag behöver en Thompson, Magnum.
Maybe a shotgun. Can you raise that for me?
Kanske en hagelbössa. Kan du fixa det?
- Takes a lot of cash, Max. - What is this?
- Det krävs pengar. - Vad är det här?
It's a piece of shit. We took it off a drunk.
Det är bara skit. Tog den från ett fyllo.
- Does it work? - I don't know. I don't play with those.
- Funkar den? - Vet inte. Jag sysslar inte med sånt.
- Makes my dick hard. - It's yours.
- Ger mig ståfräs. - Den är din.
You put up the money, I'll take care of you.
Fixa pengar, så tar jag hand om dig.
- I ain't got that kind of cash. - You're doing a lot of business out there.
- Jag har inte såna summor. - Du har mycket kunder.
How much time do you need?
Hur lång tid behöver du?
- Give me a couple of days. - You got it.
- Ge mig några dagar. - Visst.
I read you, Manny. Try for it tonight. I'll call your house in the morning.
Försök fixa det i kväll. Jag kommer hem till dig i morgon.
Give me one full day. Go that way. Go the side way.
Ge mig en hel dag. Gå ut på sidan.
One full day.
En hel dag.
Take it easy and you won't get hurt.
Ta det lugnt, så skadas ingen.
Give me the money.
Ge mig pengarna.
Open the register.
Öppna kassalådan.
Does he speak English?
Kan han engelska?
Better tell him to open the register.
Säg åt honom att öppna kassan.
Open the fucking register or I'll blow your fucking head off.
Öppna kassalådan annars blåser jag skallen av dig.
- Open it. You feel that? You feel that? - Yeah.
- Öppna. Känner du det? - Ja.
Open it.
Öppna.
Get down. Get down.
Ner. Ner.
Hold it.
Stanna kvar.
Don't move.
Rör er inte.
Don't come out.
Kom inte ut.
What are you thinking about?
Vad tänker du på?
You know you're breaking the law right now?
Vet du att du bryter mot lagen just nu?
What do you mean?
Vad menar du?
I mean, a cop could knock on that door, put you in jail.
Jag menar, en snut kan knacka på dörren och sätta dig i fängelse.
Why would he do that?
Varför skulle han det?
You're harboring a fugitive.
Du hjälper en rymling.
I jumped my parole yesterday. I'm on the run.
Jag bröt mot villkorligheten igår. Jag är på rymmen.
I'll take my chances.
Jag tar mina chanser.
No, I don't want any.
Nej, jag vill inte ha.
I'd like to take you out tonight...
Jag skulle vilja gå ut med dig ikväll...
...but I got some business to do with some people...
...men jag har lite affärer att ta hand om...
...so why don't you just let me borrow your car for a while?
...så kan inte jag få låna din bil ett tag?
Okay.
Jovisst.
Promise not to steal it?
Lovar du att inte stjäla den?
Gotta go to work in the morning.
Jag måste till jobbet i morgon.
- Damn, you scared me. - Hey, Max.
Fan, vad du skrämde mig.
Mickey. How you been?
Mickey. Hur har du det?
- All right. When did you raise? - A couple days ago.
- När kom du ut? - För ett par dagar sedan.
- Where'd you get those threads? - Bought them. Let's go sit down, friend.
- Var kommer kläderna ifrån? - Jag har köpt dem. Slå dig ner.
You're looking good.
Du ser bra ut.
- Slick. - Yeah.
- Snyggt. - Ja.
- It's good to see you. - You too.
- Kul att se dig. - Dig med.
Why don't you let us have that seat...
Låt oss få dem platsen-
...so me and my friend can talk some business?
- så vi kan prata lite affärer?
- So how have you been? - How long have you been around?
- Hur har du haft det? - Hur länge har du varit här?
I don't know. A couple years.
Jag vet inte. Ett par år.
- Want a drink? - Yeah.
- Vill du ha något att dricka? - Ja.
- Tommy. - Double Jack Daniel's with a 7 back.
- Tommy. - En dubbel Jack Daniel's.
- What do you want? - I'll have one of these things right here.
- Vad vill du ha? - Jag vill ha en sån här.
How you been?
Hur har du haft det?
Ready to make a move.
Jag är redo att göra ett jobb.
You got something you wanna run by me?
Har du något åt mig?
I got a sweet poker game in the Valley you might be interested in.
Jag har ett pokerspel som kan intressera dig.
- Sounds good. What's it good for? - Fifteen or 20 big ones.
- Låter bra. Vad är det värt? - Femton eller tjugo lakan.
That much? Any guns?
Så mycket? Några vapen?
No, just some fat-ass old men, man.
Nej, bara några feta gubbar.
They got pacemakers that'll short-circuit when you charge through the door.
De har pacemakers som kortsluter när ni kommer.
All right, I'm interested.
Jag är intresserad.
Can you help me with a partner?
Kan du fixa partner åt mig?
What about Kelly Mason? He comes here all the time.
Vad sägs om Kelly Mason?
He'd jump at the chance to work with you.
Han skulle gärna jobba med dig.
Who's that kid that just got up?
Vem är den unga killen där?
That's Augie Morales' brother.
Det är Augie Morales lillebror.
- Is that Augie's kid brother? - Yeah.
- Är det Augies lillebror? - Ja.
- Get him over here. - Hey, Chungie. Come here.
- Ta hit honom. - Chungie. Kom hit.
- How you doing? - Nice to see you again.
- Hur är det? - Trevligt att ses.
This is Max Dembo, man. He's a good friend of Augie's.
Det här är Max Dembo. Han är en god vän till Augie.
- Hi. - You don't remember me, do you?
- Hej. - Du kommer inte ihåg mig, va?
- You're a friend of my brother's, right? - How's he doing?
- Du är kompis med min bror, va? - Hur har han det?
He's not doing very well right now. He's doing 20 years in Arizona...
Han har det inte så bra. Han gör 20 år i Arizona-
...and has a lot of problems in California too.
- och han har problem i Kalifornien också.
- Can you vouch for him? - He's as good as Augie was at that age.
- Går du i god för honom? - Han är lika bra som Augie var.
Can I get ahold of him through you?
Får jag tag på honom hos dig?
I got his phone number, or you can catch him in here.
Jag har hans nummer, eller så ses ni här.
I got something for you, maybe. We'll talk later, okay?
Jag har kanske något åt dig. Vi hörs.
- Just give me a call. - Give my love to your brother.
- Slå mig en signal. - Hälsa din bror.
- I will. Thanks very much. See you later. - All right, take care.
- Det ska jag. Tack. Vi ses. - Ta det lugnt.
- Does he take shit? - No, he's too smart for that.
- Tar han droger? - Nej, han är för smart för det.
He's a good thief for his age.
Bra tjuv för sin ålder.
Know what I'd like to do?
Vet du vad jag vill?
Run me by that motel. We'll check it out, then go cut it up.
Kör mig till motellet. Vi kollar det, sen tar vi det.
I'll drive you out there, but I'm not gonna rob it for you.
Jag kör dit dig, men jag rånar det inte åt dig.
You've got to do that yourself, you know. I got stomach trouble.
Det får du göra själv, Jag har magproblem.
No guts.
Ingen stake.
Did I scare you?
Skrämde jag dig?
Yeah, a little bit.
Ja, lite grann.
You gotta go to work pretty soon.
Du måste åka till jobbet snart.
What time is it?
Vad är klockan?
Wanna take a shower with me?
Vill du ta en dusch med mig?
Can I use your phone?
Får jag låna telefonen?
Yeah, go ahead.
Javisst.
Is Jerry Schue there?
Är Jerry Schue där?
- Looks like you're fixed up pretty good. - It's going all right.
- Du har fått det bra. - Ja, det går bra.
After you fell, I pulled a few jobs and met Carol.
Efter att du åkte in träffade jag Carol.
She straightened me out...
Hon fick ordning på mig-
...so I set myself up in the painting/contracting business. Sit here.
- så jag började i måleribranschen. Slå dig ner.
We bought the house.
Vi köpte huset.
I got that boat. Put the pool in last year. The only thing I need's a new car.
Jag skaffade båten. Byggde poolen förra året. Jag behöver bara ny bil.
The one out front belonged to Carol's ex. It's about had it.
Den på framsidan tillhörde Carols ex. Den är slut.
When you were at Quentin, did you know a guy named Don Shaffer?
När du satt på Quentin, kände du en Don Shaffer?
- I don't think so. - Kind of a short, squat guy.
- Jag tror inte det. - En kort, satt typ.
- He was my first husband. - He don't know the man, honey.
- Det var min första man. - Han känner honom inte.
- You got a place in town, Max, or what? - Nickname "Lumpy."
- Bor du i sta'n eller? - Kallades "Lumpy."
I know him. Was that your first husband?
Jag känner honom. Var det din första man?
Yeah, I know Lumpy.
Ja, jag känner Lumpy.
What are we gonna do, honey, go down the whole damn list?
Vad ska vi göra gå igenom hela listan?
First there was Lumpy, then it was Steve the bodybuilder...
Först var det Lumpy, sen bodybuildern Steve-
...greased himself to death...
- oljade ihjäl sig-
...then Raymond, who sold us the lemon out front.
- sen Raymond, som sålde skrothögen till oss.
- Did I leave any out? - Oh, will you cut it out?
- Har jag glömt någon? - Kan du lägga av?
So how'd you two lovebirds meet?
Så hur träffades ni turturduvor?
I met her at a 31 Flavors, of all places.
Jag träffade henne på glasstället "31 Smaker".
Yeah, he was 32.
Han var smak 32.
Isn't she a peach?
Är hon inte underbar?
Why don't we get Sherry and we could all go out dancing later?
Kan vi inte ta med Sherry och gå ut och dansa?
Oh, you mean Sherry, that blond that threw up in the car...
Du menar Sherry, blondinen som spydde i bilen-
...the last time we went out?
- senast vi gick ut?
I know the kind of broad he wants. A good-Iooking broad. Marlene.
Jag vet vad han vill ha för tjej. En snygg brud. Marlene.
- I'd really like a beer, if you have one. - Sure, I got beer.
- Jag skulle vilja ha en öl. - Visst, jag har öl.
- Want everything on these burgers? - Yeah.
- Vill du ha allt på burgarna? - Ja.
Okay. Here.
Varsågod.
Thanks.
Tack.
- I'll be right back. - Okay.
- Jag kommer snart. - Visst.
Thank you, honey.
Tack, älskling.
Not bad.
Inte dålig.
Get me out of here.
Ta mig härifrån.
They're killing me. I can't make this scene any more.
De tar livet av mig. Jag klarar det inte längre.
Get me out of here.
Ta mig härifrån.
You got something. I know you got something.
Du har något på gång.
Yeah, I got something.
Ja, jag har något på gång.
Well, let's do it.
Då gör vi det.
- Don't you wanna know what it is? - I don't give a damn. Let's just do it.
- Vill du inte veta vad det är? - Det skiter jag i. Vi gör det.
What is it?
Vad är det?
A bunch of old guys play poker over in a motel in the Valley.
Ett gäng gamla gubbar spelar poker på ett motell.
They got about $20,000 on the table.
De har runt 20000 på bordet.
We just tiptoe in, tiptoe out, and it's all ours.
Vi smyger in, vi smyger ut och det är vårt.
There ain't no cops because they can't call.
Och de kan inte ringa polisen.
- Great. You got the guns? - Yeah.
- Toppen. Har du vapen? - Ja.
- We need a shotgun. - Here, honey.
- Vi behöver en hagelbössa. - Varsågod, raring.
I don't know what to play.
Jag vet inte vad jag ska spela.
- You still playing that thing? - I'm eating, for chrissake.
- Spelar du fortfarande? - Jag äter, för sjutton.
You can play later, but I'd prefer now.
Du kan spela sen, men helst nu.
Play that song where you yodel.
Spela den där du joddlar.
What's that "Walking Stick" thing you used to play?
Den där "Walking Stick" som du brukar spela?
What "Walking Stick"? You mean "Hand Me Down My Walking Cane"?
Vilken "Walking Stick"? Menar du "Hand Me Down My Walking Cane"?
"Walking Cane," yeah, play that.
"Walking Cane," ja, spela den.
Come on, we got cause to celebrate.
Kom igen, vi ska fira.
Alrighty.
Javisst.
Oh, shit, Max.
Fan också, Max.
All right, Jerry. Take it easy. We're all right. He'll be here.
Okej, Jerry. Ta det lugnt. Han dyker upp.
Man, this is very unprofessional.
Det här är oprofessionellt.
All I'm saying is you give the man 10 minutes.
Ge honom tio minuter.
He'll be here. It's all right.
Han kommer. Det är lugnt.
It's not all right, man. I've had it. Get me out of here.
Det är inte lugnt. Jag har fått nog. Släpp ut mig.
Is that him?
Är det han?
No. If it was him, he would have stopped.
Nej. Var det han, hade han stannat.
That's it. They're coming out. It's over. Let's go.
De kommer ut nu. Det är kört.
We're still all right. We still can do it, man.
Det är lugnt. Vi kan göra det.
It's over, man. Look at the people. They're coming out, man.
Det är kört. Titta på allt folk. De kommer ut.
I mean, I don't care if he shows up with a 20 mm cannon. It's over.
Det spelar ingen roll om han kommer med en 20 mm kanon.
Fuck it.
Fan också.
Jesus. Will you wait a minute, man? They'll see you.
Jösses. Kan du ta det lugnt? De kan se dig.
We're all right. There's five more guys in there. Let's do it.
Det är lugnt. Det är fem man kvar där inne. Vi kan göra det.
I told you, I'm not taking that game without a shotgun.
Jag gör det inte utan en hagelbössa.
You can't cover a fucking poker game without a shotgun, all right?
Man kan inte täcka ett pokerspel utan hagelbössa, okej?
The plan was to meet your friend here with a shotgun...
Planen var att möta din vän med vapnet-
...we go in and do the job and we leave, all right?
- vi skulle göra jobbet och vi skulle dra.
Now, we've been sitting here all night waiting for the guy with the shotgun...
Nu har vi suttit här hela natten och väntat på vapen-killen-
...and you wanna take it with your cap pistol...
- och du vill göra det med knallpulverpistolen-
...and I'm telling you it's very un-fucking-professional, all right?
- och jag säger att det är jävligt oprofessionellt, okej?
- That's him. - If that's him, tell him he's late.
- Där är han. - Om det är han, säg att han är sen.
- How you doing? - What's to it, Manny?
- Hur är det? - Hur går det, Manny?
Some really fucking weird shit. You know the bartender, the asshole...
Helt jävla åt helvete. Du vet den jävla bartendern...
What do you got for me?
Vad har du åt mig?
Go ahead.
Fortsätt.
I was just gonna... I didn't come with nothing...
Jag skulle just... Jag har inte med något-
...because the bartender, I gave him the key to my place to lock up...
- för att bartendern, jag gav honom nycklarna för att...
So, what'd you bring me?
Så vad har du med dig?
- I didn't bring you nothing. But I... - Just tell me, why weren't you here?
- Jag har inte med någonting. Men... - Varför var du inte här?
- Well, will you let me explain, Max? - Yeah, go ahead.
- Kan du låta mig förklara, Max? - Visst.
There's people up there. They're gonna see you.
Det är folk där, de kan se dig.
- Are you out of your mind? - Sorry.
- Är du helt galen? - Förlåt.
Come on, man. Calm down. You made your point.
Lugna ner dig. Du har gjort din åsikt känd.
You were righteous, okay? Cool it, man. Just cool it.
Du hade rätt, okej? Ta det lugnt nu.
We fucked the score off on... Hey, hey!
Det gick åt helvete...
We fucked the score off on account of you, you know that?
Det gick åt helvete på grund av dig.
Will you just settle down? Get in the car. Please.
Kan du ta det lugnt? Sätt dig i bilen. Snälla.
You know, I counted on him. He let me down. He was wrong.
Jag räknade med honom. Han svek mig. Han hade fel.
- So get in the car. - He was wrong. He let me down.
- Sätt dig i bilen. - Han hade fel. Han svek mig.
Hey, get in the car. This ain't gonna make it, man. Okay?
Sätt dig i bilen. Det här kommer inte att funka.
You're wrong, Manny. You know that?
Du har fel, Manny.
- You know that you're wrong, right? - Come on. There's no money in this.
- Du vet att du har fel, va? - Det ligger inga pengar i det här.
How's it feel getting fucked out of 20 grand?
Tänk att bli blåst på 20000?
It ain't no big thing. I just wanna get you home.
Det spelar ingen roll. Jag vill bara få hem dig.
Let's go. It's cold.
Kom nu. Det är kallt.
- I've gotta cool this dude down. - He won't tell.
- Jag måste kyla ner honom. - Han säger inget.
I'm gonna make sure so I can keep you on the streets. Turn the key.
Jag måste vara säker så du kan vara kvar ute.
- I'm all right. - You going home?
- Det är lugnt. - Åker du hem?
Tell me the truth. You going home? You know what you're doing?
Åker du hem? Vet du vad du gör?
- I won't let you down next time. - Turn your lights on.
- Jag sviker er inte nästa gång. - Sätt på lyset.
Come on, baby.
Kom igen.
Shit.
Fan.
Fucker.
Jävlar.
Hi.
Hej.
What happened? Where've you been?
Var har du varit?
I had to take care of some business.
Jag hade lite att fixa.
What kind of business? Why are you all dirty?
Vad då för något? Varför är du smutsig?
I broke through a wall.
Jag tog mig genom en vägg.
Why?
Varför?
I did something.
Jag gjorde en grej.
The place looks nice.
Det ser trevligt ut.
What made you finally decide to unpack?
Vad gjorde att du packade upp?
How far you wanna take this?
Hur långt vill du ta det?
I don't know.
Jag vet inte.
I thought we were working on something here, but maybe I'm wrong.
Jag trodde att vi hade något men kanske har jag fel.
No. What do you think I've been doing?
Nej. Vad tror du att jag gjort?
Guess I never really thought about it.
Jag har inte riktigt tänkt på det.
Want me to lie and say I work on a hot-dog stand? I can't do a regular job.
Vill du att jag ska ljuga och säga att jag säljer varm-korv?
I'm not gonna take your money.
Jag ska inte ta dina pengar.
Well, do you have an alternative for me?
Har du ett alternativ åt mig?
I'm doing what I do.
Jag gör det jag gör.
If you can't take it and it's too heavy for you...
Om du inte klarar det och det är för mycket-
...well, then I'll just walk out the door.
- då går jag bara.
I'll walk, but I don't want to.
Jag går, men jag vill inte det.
Was this just a one-time thing, or what?
Var det här en engångsgrej, eller?
That depends on how lucky I get.
Det beror på om jag har tur.
The thing I had going got screwed up, so I did another thing.
Det jag hade på gång gick snett.
I'm just trying to get myself together, you know?
Jag försöker bara samla mig.
If I could just get a decent score, just put one thing together...
Kan jag bara göra ett bra jobb-
...then we can kick back and maybe we can get out of here. That's all.
- så kan vi ta det lugnt och kanske dra härifrån. Det är allt.
So I guess what we're really saying here is if I can handle it.
Det vi säger är väl om jag kan klara det.
- That's right. - I don't want you to go.
- Ja. - Jag vill inte att du går.
And I don't want to either.
Det vill inte jag heller.
It's just that this is so totally out of my experience. You gotta understand.
Det är bara så helt nytt för mig. Du måste förstå.
I'll promise you that I won't hurt you, and whatever I do doesn't involve you.
Jag lovar att inte skada dig och att inte blanda in dig i något.
I keep it outside.
Jag håller det utanför.
But maybe it'd be better if you didn't ask me questions.
Men kanske är det bäst att du inte frågar.
I'll stay with you as long as I can handle it, but when I can't, I'm gonna go.
Jag är med dig så länge jag kan. När jag inte klarar mer, går jag.
I know that.
Jag vet det.
Just be careful.
Var bara försiktig.
I want you to know that what you're doing out there...
Jag vill att du ska veta att det du gör-
...it scares the shit out of me.
- skrämmer skiten ur mig.
It scares me too.
Det skrämmer mig också.
Come here.
Kom hit.
You come here.
Du får komma hit.
- Can I give you something? - What is it?
- Får jag ge dig en sak? - Vad är det?
Something I found.
Något jag hittat.
Come on, now. Don't be scared.
Kom. Var inte rädd.
Don't be scared.
Var inte rädd.
I can't help it.
Jag kan inte rå för det.
Excuse me, sir, would you look right over there, please?
Ursäkta mig kan du titta dit bort?
All right, don't move. Get up out of there.
Rör dig inte. Kom upp därifrån.
Get the fuck out of there, man.
Stick härifrån.
Get in there.
Gå in dit.
All right, listen to me! This is a robbery! Everybody on the floor.
Hör upp. Detta är ett rån! Alla ska lägga sig på golvet.
- Get down on the goddamn floor! - Open the drawer.
- Ner på det jävla golvet! - Öppna lådan.
All the way down. All you tellers, down on the floor.
Hela vägen ner. Alla kassörer, ner på golvet.
All the way down! Hey, get down!
Hela vägen ner!
Open the drawer. Open it up.
Öppna lådan.
Get down before I start killing people!
Ner, innan jag börjar döda folk!
Get your drawer open, honey. Get your drawer open.
Öppna din låda, raring.
Stop looking at me!
Sluta titta på mig!
Get down on the goddamn floor!
Ner på golvet!
Thirty seconds.
Trettio sekunder.
Twenty seconds.
Tjugo sekunder.
You in love with me? Answer me! Are you in love with me?
Är du kär i mig? Svara! Är du kär i mig?
Then stop looking at me, motherfucker, or I'll blow your goddamn face off!
Sluta titta då, innan jag blåser skallen av dig!
Time's up. Let's go.
Tiden är slut. Nu sticker vi.
Let's go.
Nu sticker vi.
Let's go!
Kom nu!
Let's hit it.
Nu drar vi.
Get back!
Stanna där!
Get back. Get down on the floor!
Ner på golvet!
Let's go.
Kom nu.
- How much did we get? - We got a bunch.
- Hur mycket fick vi? - Vi fick en del.
- How was I? Was I good? - You scared the shit out of me.
- Hur var jag? Var jag bra? - Du skrämde skiten ur mig.
Hit it, hit it. Just hit it. Hit it. Let's go.
Gasen i botten. Kör.
Make a left here.
Ta vänster här.
- What do we got? - I don't know. I can't tell yet. It's fat.
- Hur mycket har vi? - Jag vet inte än. Det är mycket.
- What is it? Twenties, 30s, 50s? - Yeah, there's 20s. There's no 30s, man.
- Vad är det? Tjugor, trettiolappar? - Det är tjugolappar. Inga trettio.
- Any ones? - Yeah, there's a few ones.
- Några? - Ja, några stycken.
- A couple hundreds. - Would you say, 20, 30,000? Forty?
- Några hundra. - Vad tror du? Trettiotusen? Fyrtio?
What's that look like? What's that look like to you, huh?
Vad ser det ut som?
- What's this look like, huh? - Let me feel it.
- Vad ser det ut som? - Får jag känna.
Come on. Asshole.
Kom igen. Arsel.
Put it up your fucking snoot, baby.
Rätt upp i näsan.
- Man. - We got more fucking money here...
Vi har mer pengar här än...
Let's go over to your place and cut it up.
Vi åker till dig och delar upp det.
- Put it in the bathroom, lock the door... - Right on the floor.
- Vi har det i badrummet, låser dörren... - Rätt på golvet.
From now on, when I say go, though, man, we gotta go, man.
När jag säger att vi ska dra, så drar vi.
- When I yell, "Go," go. - The clock...
När jag säger till så drar vi.
The clock, my ass. We always go through this shit.
Vi går alltid igenom det här.
I'll dock you 8 grand you stopped me from getting from that last teller.
Jag drar av de åtta tusen du hindrade mig från att ta.
Eight thousand fucking dollars.
Åtta tusen jävla dollar.
It was like pulling teeth to get you out of the fucking place.
Det är som att dra ut en tand att få ut dig därifrån.
So we scored.
Vi gick med vinst.
- Do you like it? - Not really. What are we doing here?
- Tycker du om det? - Inte riktigt. Vad gör vi här?
Let me buy you something. What about the earrings?
Jag vill ge dig något. Vad sägs om örhängena?
- I think it's a set. - Look at the ring.
- De hör nog ihop. - Titta på ringen.
The price tag on it's $9135.
Den kostar 9135 dollar.
- I bet that bracelet's worth more than... - Hello. May I help you?
- Armbandet är nog värt mer än... - Kan jag stå till tjänst?
- How much is that? - Eighteen thousand.
- Hur mycket kostar det? - 18000.
- What about this one here? - Forty-seven five for the set.
- Den här då? - 47500.
- With tax or without? - Without tax.
- Med eller utan moms? - Utan.
Want a watch? Where's ladies' watches?
Vill du ha en klocka?
This counter right over here.
Här har vi damur.
What are you doing?
Vad gör du?
- I'm getting you a watch. - I don't want a watch.
- Jag ger dig en klocka. - Jag vill inte ha det.
- Hi. - Hi. May I show you something?
- Hej. - Vill ni se på något?
- Can we see some ladies' watches? - Certainly.
Kan vi få se några damklockor?
- This entire counter, all ladies' watches. - How about your best one?
- Hela disken här är damur. - Vilken är bäst?
Best one? Is right here.
Bäst? Den här.
- That's all right. - Isn't that a lovely watch?
Är den inte förtjusande?
It's disgusting.
Den är gräslig.
- Let's see this one here. - Certainly.
- Få se på den. - Ja visst.
- I don't like those diamonds. - Let me put this back.
Jag gillar inte diamanterna.
That's nice.
Den var fin.
- How much is that? - That's $2000.
- Vad kostar den? - Den kostar 2000.
I can't wear that to work.
Jag kan inte ha den till jobbet.
Better show us something less expensive. She has very simple tastes.
Visa oss något mindre exklusivt. Hon har enkel smak.
It's my upbringing. What can I tell you?
Det är min bakgrund.
Here, let's try this one.
Prova den.
- How much is that one? - This one is $900.
- Hur mycket kostar den? - Den kostar 900.
That's pretty. What make is that?
Den är söt. Vad är det för märke?
Sir? Excuse me.
Sir? Ursäkta mig.
Where are you going?
Vart går ni?
I was just looking for your restroom.
Jag letade efter toaletten.
I'm sorry, but we don't have a public restroom here.
Jag är ledsen, men vi har ingen kundtoalett.
There's a coffee shop two doors down. They'll allow you to use their facilities.
Det finns ett kafé längre bort. Där har de toalett.
Thanks. Did you get what you wanted?
Tack. Fick du det du ville?
- I like this the best. - We'll have to think about it.
- Jag gillar den mest. - Vi får fundera på det.
- Very well. - We'll be back.
- Ja visst. - Vi återkommer.
- Thank you for coming in. - Bye-bye.
- Tack för besöket. - Hej då.
- Is there anything else to see upstairs? - No, those are the executive offices.
- Finns det något på övervåningen? - Nej, bara kontor.
Look, this is Wilshire Boulevard right here, right?
Här är Wilshire Boulevard alldeles här, okej?
All right. Here's the doors.
Här är dörrarna.
There's glass windows on either side, and they're tinted, Jerry.
Det är fönster på sidorna, och de är tonade.
From the outside, you cannot see in.
Från utsidan kan man inte se in.
But inside, you can see all the action outside.
Men inifrån kan man se ut.
We didn't have that on the bank, right?
Så var det inte på banken, eller hur?
When I was in there, the lady showed me one case.
När jag var där, visade damen mig en disk.
In one case, there was over 125 grand of ice there.
Bara i den fanns det glitter för 125000.
In one case?
I en enda disk?
What do you think?
Vad tror du?
I don't know.
Jag vet inte.
Beverly Hills is rough, man. Scares the shit out of me, Beverly Hills.
Beverly Hills är tufft. Skrämmer skiten ur mig, Beverly Hills.
Why's that?
Varför det?
I don't know. Well, how many cops they got there?
Jag vet inte. Hur många snutar har de där?
They got 100 cops in six square miles, you know.
De har 100 snutar på en kvadratmil.
That's, you know, 20 cops to the square mile, or whatever it is.
Det är tjugo snutar per kvadratkilometer eller något.
What's the response time? Three minutes?
Hur snabbt rycker de ut?
- Three minutes? - What'd make you feel safe in there?
- Tre minuter? - Vad vill du ha för att vara säker?
Fuck Beverly Hills. Fuck those cops, man. They're just cops.
Fan ta Beverly Hills. Fan ta snutarna. De är bara snutar.
They can't be faster than three minutes. Alarm goes off when we start sacking.
De kan inte vara snabbare är tre minuter. Larmet går när vi plockar.
Let the alarm go.
Låt larmet gå.
Would you feel safe for a minute and a half?
Skulle du känna dig säker i en och en halv minut?
Bob. I gotta get out of here, man.
Jag måste härifrån.
They're waiting on me.
De väntar på mig.
Tell the old lady that owns the house to sign this, not her mother, all right?
Se till att damen som äger huset skriver på, inte hennes mor.
- All right. - Right up.
Okej.
You know next week you don't have to do that?
Du vet att nästa vecka behöver du inte göra det där?
- I wanna see you with nice clothes. - How much longer you gonna be?
Hur lång tid tar det?
- Yeah, I'll be there in a minute. - Okay.
- Jag kommer snart. - Okej.
Don't you wanna tan your face? You wanna live in that neighborhood?
Vill du inte sola dig? Vill du bo i det området?
Don't you want a new car?
Vill du inte ha en ny bil?
You're a thief. Why don't you be a thief?
Du är en tjuv. Var då en tjuv.
Did you like doing that bank?
Gillade du att råna banken?
Did you feel good doing that bank, holding that shotgun?
Kändes det bra i banken, att hålla vapnet?
- Did you feel good working with me? - Yeah.
- Kändes det bra att jobba med mig? - Ja.
You wanna do it?
Vill du göra det?
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
Ja.
Yeah. What about a driver?
Hur blir det med förare?
Mickey Barber, the other night, introduced me to a guy.
Mickey Barber presenterade mig för en kille.
I knew his brother.
Jag kände hans bror.
He said he's a good wheelman.
Han sa att det är en bra förare.
- How you doing? - Good.
- Hur är det? - Bra.
- Jerry, Willy. - Hey, man, I've heard a lot about you.
- Jerry, Willy. - Jag har hört talas om dig.
Here. I'll get it for you.
Jag fixar det.
Watch your feet.
Se upp.
- Who is that guy? - What?
- Vem är det? - Va?
- Is that the guy Mickey sent? - No.
- Är det Mickeys kille? - Nej.
- No? - It fell through.
- Inte? - Det gick snett.
- What do you mean? - Did you get the plates changed?
- Vad menar du? - Har du bytt nummerplåtar?
The car is one half-hour hot and the plates are changed. I did everything.
Bilen är stulen för en halv- timme sedan och plåtarna är bytta.
You should've told me. That was wrong. Do you hear me? That was wrong.
Du skulle ha sagt till mig. Hör du det? Det var fel.
- Where are we going? - Keep going. We'll talk about it later.
- Vart ska vi? - Kör på. Vi tar det sen.
- Right here? - Go straight toward it.
- Här? - Kör rakt på.
All right. Now, you're gonna back in that first spot there.
Backa in på första platsen här.
Go ahead. Take it easy.
Kom igen. Ta det lugnt.
Soon as you get in, I'll tell you what we're doing.
Så fort vi är inne, ska jag berätta vad vi ska göra.
- Oh, shit, I'm sorry. - Take it easy, all right?
- Fan. Ursäkta. - Ta det lugnt, okej?
Okay, you see that door over there? We'll be out in a few minutes.
Ser du dörren där borta? Vi kommer ut om några minuter.
As soon as we're out, open both doors. We get in and split. You got it?
Då öppnar du båda dörrarna. Vi kommer in, och sen drar vi.
- Yeah. - How do you feel?
- Ja. - Hur känns det?
- Do I keep the car running? - Yeah. All right?
- Låter jag motorn gå? - Ja. Okej?
- I'm okay. - You ready to hit it?
- Jag är okej. - Är du redo att slå till?
- Yeah. - All right, let's go.
- Ja. - Då kör vi igång.
Just relax, man.
Ta det bara lugnt.
How do you feel?
Hur känner du dig?
Feel great. Except for that driver, man.
Bra. Förutom med föraren.
Don't worry about it.
Oroa dig inte.
- You should have told me about it. - All right, let's do this.
- Du skulle sagt något om det. - Nu kör vi.
- How's the vibes? - Everything's all right.
- Hur verkar det? - Allt verkar bra.
- A lot of traffic, a lot of people. - I'd kiss you, but you're too ugly.
- Mycket trafik, mycket folk. - Du är för ful för en kyss.
No, it's too yellow. Thank you.
Den är för gul. Tack.
Well, may I see the 10 mm, please?
Kan jag få se den på 10 mm?
Yes.
Ja.
Well, yes, I like the pink...
Ja, jag gillar den rosa...
- I need a 24-carat ring. - Well, we can order that. No problem.
- Jag behöver en ring på 24 karat. - Det kan vi beställa. Inga problem.
What about...?
Hur blir...?
Pardon me. What are you doing?
Ursäkta. Vad sysslar ni med?
Can you step back, please?
Kan du stiga undan, tack?
Do what you're told and you won't get hurt.
Gör som vi säger, så går det bra.
Get up against the wall! Face the wall!
Ställ er mot väggen! Titta på väggen!
Sorry, sir. Will you step back in there before you get shot?
Ursäkta. Kan ni gå tillbaka innan ni blir skjuten?
- How do you feel? - Go ahead, get some.
- Hur känner du dig? - Det går bra.
- We've got a minute and a half. - Go on, there.
- Vi har en och en halv minut. - Kör på.
What's the time?
Hur ligger vi till?
- What's the time? - One minute.
- Hur ligger vi till? - En minut.
Get it all.
Ta allt.
Twenty seconds to go.
Tjugo sekunder till.
Let's go.
Då sticker vi.
- Let's go! Let's hit it. - We've got time.
- Nu drar vi. - Vi har tid.
Time's up! Let's go!
Tiden är slut! Nu sticker vi!
Let's go, man. We've gotta get out of here.
Kom igen. Vi måste härifrån.
There was another piece here.
Det fanns en till här.
I don't believe this, man. I really don't believe this.
Det är helt otroligt.
- There's gonna be an army out there. - Where was it?
Det kommer att vara en armé utanför.
- I don't know. - There was a big piece here.
Det var en stor grej här.
This is the last goddamn time, man. This is it.
Det här var sista gången.
The poker game was the same way, the driver, the whole goddamn thing.
Pokerspelet var likadant, föraren, hela jävla grejen.
This is it. It's all over.
Nu räcker det. Det är slut nu.
You're a child, man. You act like a 2-year-old child, for chrissake.
Du är som en unge. Du uppför dig som en 2-åring.
I know you like a book.
Jag känner dig så väl.
This is the last goddamn time I'm working with you. I mean it.
Det är sista gången jag jobbar med dig. Jag menar det.
What are you...? Get over there and sit down! Put your head down.
Vad är du...? Gå dit bort och sätt dig. Ner med huvudet.
- What are you doing? - Where's the watch?
- Vad gör du? - Var är klockan?
Hey, we gotta get out of here, man!
Vi måste härifrån nu!
- Listen to me! Listen to me. - Let go of that. All right, all right!
- Lyssna på mig! - Släpp det!
Give it to me, man.
Ge mig det.
- We're going. - Why don't you take a clock too?
- Vi sticker. - Ska du inte ta ett väggur också?
This is the last goddamn time I'm working with you.
Det här är fan sista gången jag jobbar med dig.
- Where is he? - Yeah, where is he?
- Var är han? - Ja, var är han?
Where is he? Was this part of your goddamn plan?
Var är han? Var det här del av planen?
Who the fuck knows where he is?
Vem i helvete vet var han är?
You're pathetic. You're a pathetic fucking human being.
Du är patetisk. Du är en jävla patetisk människa.
We gotta run. We gotta run. We gotta run.
Vi måste springa.
Get rid of the shotgun!
Gör dig av med bössan!
Walk, walk, walk. Slow down and walk. Walk.
Gå, gå, gå. Sakta ner och gå.
- Come on. - Are we going the right way?
- Kom igen. - Är vi på väg åt rätt håll?
The car's on the next street. Come on, we're all right.
Bilen står på nästa gata. Kom igen, det är lugnt.
Halt! Police!
Stanna! Polis!
- It's a great line. - We gotta go. Right now. Come on.
- Det är en bra linje. - Vi måste gå. Nu.
Excuse me, could you see this guy for me?
Kan du ta hand om honom?
- Where's your car? - In the back.
- Var är din bil? - På baksidan.
- Where? Let's go.
- Var? Kom. - Baksidan.
So I'll be back in a second. What's the matter?
Jag är strax tillbaka. Vad är det?
- Where's your key? Where's your car? - Keep going. It's over there.
- Var är nyckeln? Var är bilen? - Fortsätt. Den är där borta.
- Give me the key. - Just a sec.
- Ge mig nyckeln. - Vänta lite.
- Where are we going? - Come on.
- Vart ska vi? - Kom.
- What happened? - I'll tell you later.
- Vad hände? - Jag berättar sen.
What are you doing?
Vad gör du?
Max, please.
Max, snälla.
I gotta stop by and get some money from a friend.
Jag måste hämta pengar hos en vän.
Where are you, man? Willy?
Var är du? Willy?
Shit.
Fan.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Vänta, vänta, vänta.
I'll fucking hurt your fucking ass.
Jag ska fan göra dig illa.
Don't tell me "wait." I'm gonna put your fucking brains on that wall!
Säg inte vänta! Jag ska sätta din hjärna på väggen!
- Let me explain. - You knew I'd be back, didn't you?
- Låt mig förklara. - Du visste väl att jag skulle komma?
Please let me explain to you what happened.
Låt mig förklara vad som hände.
Go ahead, run it.
Varsågod, dra det.
I had the car pointed the right way.
Jag hade bilen åt rätt håll.
The motor was on.
Motorn var på.
I was watching my clock, I was watching the door.
Jag tittade på klockan, jag tittade på dörren.
The burglar alarm went off for five minutes.
Larmet gick i fem minuter.
That's bullshit, man.
Det är skitsnack.
- Max... - No, no. No, man, I would've been there.
- Max... - Nej, jag hade varit där.
I'm running because of you, sucker man.
Jag flyr på grund av dig.
That shit under the bed? I went to jail because of you.
Skiten under sängen? Jag satt i häktet för det.
I'm sorry.
Jag är ledsen.
Well, you know, sorry ain't shit now. You know why?
Vet du, ledsen betyder ingenting. Vet du varför?
It don't mean nothing.
Det betyder ingenting.
Come on, Max.
Kom igen, Max.
- Are you high? - No.
- Är du hög? - Nej.
- Did you get high?
- Var du hög?
Then I don't understand why you don't hear me.
Då förstår jag inte varför du inte hör.
I don't understand why you don't understand what I'm talking about.
Jag förstår inte varför du inte förstår vad jag pratar om.
Jerry's dead.
Jerry är död.
Just lying on the street, man.
Han ligger på gatan.
And that hurts me, man, because he'd do anything for me.
Det gör ont, för han gjorde allt för mig.
He'd do anything for me.
Han gjorde allt.
If he was out in the car, man...
Hade han varit ute i bilen-
...there could have been a shitstorm, you know?
- kunde vad som helst ha hänt.
Max, I'm sorry.
Max, jag är ledsen.
I got scared.
Jag blev rädd.
I'm scared now.
Jag är rädd nu.
You did the best you could, right?
Du gjorde ditt bästa, eller hur?
- I really did. - I gave you every chance, too, didn't I?
- Det gjorde jag. - Jag gav dig alla chanser, eller hur?
It wasn't your fault.
Det var inte ditt fel.
It's over, Willy.
Det är över, Willy.
It's over, man. Forget it. I shouldn't have asked you to do it.
Glöm det. Jag skulle inte ha bett dig att göra det.
It was too heavy for you.
Det var för tungt för dig.
- I'm sorry. - It's all right. It's all right, man.
- Jag är ledsen. - Det är lugnt.
- What can I do? - Give me a big bear hug...
- Vad kan jag göra? - Ge mig en stor björnkram...
...and just forget it. - Okay.
...och glöm det. - Okej.
I'm sorry.
Jag är ledsen.
- You were wrong, though, you know. - I know it.
- Fast du hade fel. - Jag vet det.
I'm sorry.
Jag är ledsen.
Shit.
Fan.
Did you get it?
Fick du dem?
- What? - The money.
- Vad? - Pengarna.
Yeah.
Ja.
Where's the freeway?
Var är motorvägen?
I don't know.
Jag vet inte.
Well, we're going.
Vi kör nu.
- All right? - Let's go. Yeah, let's go.
- Okej? - Ja, vi kör nu.
How you doing?
Hur är det?
- Want me to drive? - No, I'm all right. Can I have one?
- Vill du köra? - Nej, det går bra. Kan jag få en?
- This afternoon when a house trailer lost its brakes and ran into a schoolyard.
...i eftermiddags när en husvagn utan bromsar körde in på en skolgård.
One man is dead and one wounded in a gunfight...
En man är död och en skadad efter skottlossning-
... following a jewelry store holdup in Beverly Hills earlier this afternoon.
- i samband med ett rån mot en guldsmedsbutik i eftermiddags.
The robbers, two in number...
Rånarna, som var två stycken-
... used hammers to break through the counters and display cases...
- använde hammare för att slå sönder glaset-
... in Gindel's, an exclusive Wilshire Boulevard shop.
- på Gindel's, en exklusiv butik på Wilshire Boulevard.
Police arrived just as the robbers were making their getaway...
Polisen kom just som rånarna flydde-
... and in the ensuing gun battle...
- och under skottlossningen-
... one of the holdup men, Jerry Schue, age 48, of Burbank, was killed.
- dödades en av rånarna, Jerry Schue, 48, från Burbank.
Also critically wounded in the shootout was Officer David Post...
Allvarligt skadad blev David Post-
... a two-year veteran of the force.
- som varit polis i två år.
The second holdup man, who made good his escape...
Den andre rånaren, som lyckades fly-
... has not yet been identified...
- är inte identifierad-
... but police officials are currently assembling a detailed description...
- men polisen sammanställer ett signalement-
... from eyewitnesses on the scene.
- från ögonvittnet på platsen.
Look for another smoggy day tomorrow...
I morgon blir det smog...
... according to the Air Quality Management District. Temperatures...
... och temperaturen...
We didn't start the shooting.
Vi började inte skjuta.
- Would you pull over for a second? - Why?
- Kan du stanna lite? - Varför?
Please pull over. I don't feel well.
Stanna. Jag mår inte bra.
- Wait'll we get to a gas station, will you? - I can't wait, Max.
- Kan du vänta till vi är vid macken? - Jag kan inte vänta, Max.
Pull the fucking car over, goddamn it!
Snälla stanna för fan den jävla bilen!
Max, don't you dare lay a fucking hand on me!
Max, våga inte röra mig!
- What do you wanna do with this? - I got it.
- Vad vill du göra med den? - Jag har den.
- Can I help you? - Yeah.
- Kan jag hjälpa till? - Ja.
Fill it up with regular and you better check the oil. I think that's all.
Jag vill ha full tank och kolla oljan också. Det var allt.
- Want something to drink? - Yeah.
- Vill du ha något att dricka? - Ja.
Just get me a ginger ale. I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
Ge mig en ginger ale. Jag går på toaletten.
- Give us a ginger ale and a beer? - What kind of beer?
- Kan vi få en ginger ale och en öl? - Vilken sorts öl?
- It doesn't matter. We'll be over here. - Yeah. Anyway...
- Det spelar ingen roll. - Ja. Och...
...he starts back to her at the door and I think he's not gonna say anything.
...han går tillbaka och jag tror inte han ska säga något.
And he looks up at me with the football helmet...
Han tittar på mig med fotbollshjälmen-
...and he says, "Lady, I sure hope your team wins."
- och han säger "Damen, jag hoppas ni vinner."
- Here we are, sir. Here you go. - Thank you.
- Varsågoda. - Tack.
- And can I get you something else? - No, that's okay.
- Önskas något mer? - Nej, det är bra.
I got some fine homemade chili for you.
Jag har hemgjord chili.
- This'll do it. - All right. That'll be 90 cents.
- Det räcker så här. - Då blir det 90 cent.
I saw a sign outside. Is there a bus stop here?
Är det en busshållplats här?
Yeah. That would be the local Palmdale transportation.
Ja. Det är den lokala Palmdale-linjen.
It stops twice a day.
Den stannar två gånger per dag.
The schedule's kind of irregular, but... Where were you going?
Det är lite oregelbundet, men... Vart ska ni?
- Where you kids going, honey? - L.A.
- Vart ska ni ungdomar? - L.A.
Oh, L.A. You take the Palmdale bus from here, as I say, and go into Palmdale.
Då tar ni Palmdale-bussen och åker till Palmdale.
- Make your connection to L.A. There. - What time does it get here?
- Därifrån kommer ni till L.A. - När kommer den?
You got about half an hour.
Ni har en halvtimme på er.
- I'll get your change. - Keep it.
- Ni ska få växeln. - Behåll den.
Oh, thanks, yeah.
Tack så mycket.
You sending me home?
Skickar du hem mig?
Yeah, you are.
Ja, det gör du.
Please, Max, I don't want any money.
Snälla, jag vill inte ha pengar.
I want you to have it.
Jag vill att du tar dem.
What are you gonna do?
Vart ska du?
Will you call me?
Ringer du mig?
Gotta go.
Jag måste gå.
Forgot my sweater.
Glömde min tröja.
Why can't I go with you?
Varför får jag inte följa med?
Because I wanna get caught.
För jag vill åka fast.
Subtitles by SDI Media Group
Översättning: SDI Media Group
[ENGLISH]
[SWEDISH]